I love to collect things.
أنا أحب جمع الأشياء.
Ever since I was a kid, I've had massive collections
منذ كنت طفلا، كان لدي مجموعات ضخمة
of random stuff, everything from bizarre hot sauces
من الأشياء وبشكل عشوائي، كل شيء من الصلصات الحارة الغريبة
from all around the world to insects
من جميع أنحاء العالم إلى الحشرات
that I've captured and put in jars.
التي اصطدتها ووضعتها في الجرار.
Now, it's no secret, because I like collecting things,
الآن، فإن هذا ليس سرا، لأنني أحب جمع الأشياء
that I love the Natural History Museum
التي أحبها في متحف التاريخ الطبيعي
and the collections of animals
ومجموعات الحيوانات
at the Natural History Museum in dioramas.
في "متحف التاريخ الطبيعي" في ديوراما.
These, to me, are like living sculptures, right,
وهذه، بالنسبة لي، تشبه التماثيل الحية، حقا
that you can go and look at,
يمكنك الذهاب وإلقاء نظرة عليها،
and they memorialize a specific point of time
وسوف يقومون بإحياء ذكرى فترة معينة من الزمن
in this animal's life.
في حياة هذا الحيوان.
So I was thinking about my own life,
لذلك كنت أفكر في حياتي الخاصة،
and how I'd like to memorialize my life, you know,
وكيف أود أن أخلد ذكرى حياتي، تعلمون،
for the ages, and also — (Laughter) —
لأجيال قادمة، وأيضا — (ضحك) —
the lives of my friends, but
ذكرى حياة أصدقائي، ولكن
the problem with this is that my friends aren't quite keen
مشكلة مع ذلك أن أصدقائي ليسوا حريصين جداً
on the idea of me taxidermy-ing them. (Laughter)
على فكرة تحنيطي لهم. (ضحك)
So instead, I turned to video,
فبدلاً عن ذلك، التفت إلى الفيديو،
and video is the next best way to preserve and memorialize
والفيديو هو الطريق القادم الأفضل للحفاظ على وإحياء ذكرى
someone and to capture a specific moment in time.
شخص ما ولالتقاط لحظة زمنية محددة.
So what I did was, I filmed six of my friends
لذا كان ما فعلته، هو أنني صورت ستة من أصدقائي
and then, using video mapping and video projection,
ومن ثم، باستخدام رسم خرائط الفيديو والإسقاط ،
I created a video sculpture, which was these six friends
خلقت منحوتة فيديو، والتي كانت هؤلاء الأصدقاء الستة
projected into jars. (Laughter)
مسقطين في جرار (ضحك)
So now I have this collection of my friends
الآن لدى هذه المجموعة من أصدقائي
I can take around with me whenever I go,
والتي يمكنني أخذها معي أينما ذهبت،
and this is called Animalia Chordata,
وهذا ما يسمى بالحيوانيات الفقارية،
from the Latin nomenclature for
وهي التسمية اللاتينية
human being, classification system.
للإنسان، ونظام التصنيف.
So this piece memorializes my friends in these jars,
لذلك هذا القطعة تحيي ذكرى أصدقائي في هذه الجرار،
and they actually move around. (Laughter)
ويتحركون حولها في الواقع. (ضحك)
So, this is interesting to me,
لذا، هذا مثير للاهتمام بالنسبة لي،
but it lacked a certain human element. (Laughter)
لكنها تفتقر إلى عنصر بشري معين. (ضحك)
It's a digital sculpture, so I wanted to add
إنها منحوتة رقمية، لذا كنت أريد أن أضيف لها
an interaction system. So what I did was,
نظام تفاعل. لذا كان ما فعلته،
I added a proximity sensor, so that when you get close
هو أنني أضفت جهاز استشعار عن قرب، بحيث أنك عندما تتقرب
to the people in jars, they react to you in different ways.
من الناس في الجرار، ستكون ردود أفعالهم إليك بطرق مختلفة.
You know, just like people on the street
كما تعلمون، تماما مثل الناس في الشارع
when you get too close to them.
عندما تقترب منهم كثيرا.
Some people reacted in terror. (Laughter)
بعض الناس يتجاوبون بذعر. (ضحك)
Others reacted in asking you for help,
آخرون يطلبون منك المساعدة،
and some people hide from you.
وبعض الناس يهربون منك.
So this was really interesting to me, this idea of
لذا كان هذا حقاً مثيرا للاهتمام بالنسبة لي، هذه الفكرة
taking video off the screen and putting it in real life,
لأخذ الفيديو بعيدا عن الشاشة ووضعه في الحياة الحقيقية،
and also adding interactivity to sculpture.
وأيضا إضافة التفاعل للمنحوتة.
So over the next year, I documented 40 of my other friends
لذا وعلى مدى السنة التالية، فإنني وثقت 40 من أصدقائي الآخرين
and trapped them in jars as well
وحصرتهم في الجرار، كذلك
and created a piece known as Garden,
وأنشأت القطعة المعروفة باسم حديقة،
which is literally a garden of humanity.
والتي هي حرفيا حديقة للإنسانية.
But something about the first piece,
لكن شيئا في القطعة الأولى،
the Animali Chordata piece, kept coming back to me,
قطعة "الحيوانات الفقارية"، ظل يراودني
this idea of interaction with art,
وهو تلك الفكرة عن التفاعل مع الفن،
and I really liked the idea of people being able to interact,
وأنا حقاً أحببت هذه الفكرة عن قدرة الناس على التفاعل،
and also being challenged by interacting with art.
وكذلك بأن تتعرض للتحدي من خلال هذا التفاعل مع الفن.
So I wanted to create a new piece that actually
لذا أردت أن أخلق قطعة جديدة تستطيع بالفعل
forced people to come and interact with something,
أن تجبر الناس على التفاعل مع شيء ما،
and the way I did this was actually by projecting
و الطريقة التي قمت بها بإنجاز ذلك، كانت أنني أسقطت
a 1950s housewife into a blender. (Laughter)
ربة منزل من الخمسينات في خلاط. (ضحك)
This is a piece called Blend, and what it does is
وهذه ما تسمى قطعة "مزيج"، وما تفعله
it actually makes you implicit in the work of art.
أنها فعلا تجعلك داخل إطار العمل الفني.
You may never experience the entire thing yourself.
قد لا تسطتيع أبدا أن تواجه الأمر برمته ينفسك.
You can walk away, you can just watch as this character
يمكنك المشي بعيداً، يمكنك المشاهدة فقط كهذه الشخصية
stands there in the blender and looks at you,
الواقفة هناك في الخلاط وتتطلع إليك،
or you can actually choose to interact with it.
أو يمكنك فعلا أن تختار التفاعل معها.
So if you do choose to interact with the piece,
لذا إذا اخترت التفاعل مع القطعة،
and you press the blender button, it actually sends
وقمت بالضغط على زر الخلاط، فسوف ترسل فعلا
this character into this dizzying disarray of dishevelment.
هذه الشخصية إلى حالة فوضى مذهلة.
By doing that, you are now part of my piece.
وبذلك، فأنت الآن جزء من قطعتي.
You, like the people that are trapped in my work
أنت، مثل اللأشخاص المحاصرين في عملي
— (Blender noises, laughter) —
— (ضجيج خلاط، ضحك) —
have become part of my work as well. (Laughter)
وقد أصبحت جزءا من عملي، كذلك. (ضحك)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But, but this seems a bit unfair, right?
ولكن، يبدو هذا غيرعادل قليلاً، أليس كذلك؟
I put my friends in jars, I put this character,
أضع أصدقائي في جرار، أضع هذ الشخصية،
this sort of endangered species character in a blender.
هذا النوع من الشخصيات المهددة بالانقراض في خلاط.
But I'd never done anything about myself.
ولكن لم يسبق أن فعلت أي شيء عن نفسي.
I'd never really memorialized myself.
لم يحدث أن خلدت فعلا ذكرى نفسي.
So I decided to create a piece which is a self-portrait piece.
ولذلك قررت إنشاء قطعة تمثل صورتي الذاتية.
This is sort of a self-portrait taxidermy time capsule piece
هذا النوع من الصورة الذاتية هو الذي يبقى عبر الزمن
called A Point Just Passed,
قطعة اسميتها نقطة مرّت،
in which I project myself on top of a time card punch clock,
حيث أسقطت نفسي على رأس آلة ختم ساعات العمل،
and it's up to you.
والخيار لك،
If you want to choose to punch that punch card clock,
إذا كنت تريد أن تختار أن تختم بطاقة العمل عن طريق تلك الآلة،
you actually age me.
فأنت فعليا تجعلني اكبر سنا.
So I start as a baby, and then if you punch the clock,
فأنا أبدء كرضيع صغير، وبعد ذلك إذا استخدمت آلة ختم ساعات العمل،
you'll actually transform the baby into a toddler,
فأنت فعليا ستقوم بتحويل الرضيع الى طفل،
and then from a toddler I'm transformed into a teenager.
وثم من طفل سأتحول إلى مراهق.
From a teenager, I'm transformed into my current self.
ومن مراهق، سوف أتحول إلى شكلي الحالي.
From my current self, I'm turned into a middle-aged man,
ومن شكلي الحالي، سوف أتحول إلى رجل في منتصف العمر،
and then, from there, into an elderly man.
ومن ثم، ومن هناك إلى رجل مسن.
And if you punch the punch card clock a hundred times
وإذا داومت على ختم البطاقات لمئات المرات
in one day, the piece goes black
في يوم واحد، سوف تتوقف القطعة عن العمل
and is not to be reset until the next day.
ولن تعمل مرة أخرى إلا بحلول اليوم التالي.
So, in doing so, you're erasing time.
لذا، وأنت تقوم بذلك، فأنت تمحو الوقت.
You're actually implicit in this work
فأنت في الواقع جزء من هذا العمل.
and you're erasing my life.
وأنت تمحو حياتي.
So I like this about interactive video sculpture,
لذا فالذي أحبه في منحوتات الفيديو التفاعلية،
that you can actually interact with it,
هو أنكم تسطيعون حقا أن تتفاعلوا معها،
that all of you can actually touch an artwork
وأنكم تسطيعون حقا أن تلمسوا الفن الموجود فيها
and be part of the artwork yourselves,
و تصبحوا جزء منه بأنفسكم،
and hopefully, one day, I'll have each and every one of you
وآمل، أنه في يوم ما، سأتوفر على كل واحد منكم
trapped in one of my jars. (Laughter)
محتجزا في إحدى جراري. (ضحك)
Thank you. (Applause)
شكرا لكم. (تصفيق)